Jinsong Liu

UX Designer / sylvesterlau.com

Jinsong Liu (Sylvester Lau) is a multidisciplinary designer from Guangzhou, China. He worked for three years on digital transformation in finance, retail and e-learning, and is currently a Master Student on User Experience Design. Holding a continued interest in human-technology relationships, he aspired to become a full-stack designer. His work values collaboration, measurable results but also appreciates the complex nature and unexpected processes.

EDUCATION

2020 — 2021 University of the Arts London London, United Kingdom

User Experience Design, Master of Arts

2020 — 2021 Guangdong University of Technology Guangzhou, China

Industrial Design, Bachelor of Engineering

WORK EXPERIENCE

2019 — 2020 Freelance UX/UI Designer

I mainly worked on website design using Wordpress and HTML/CSS/JS

2020 — 2021 Retail Project Design Lead Runwise Co.

Guangzhou, China

I led the design team of a digitalisation project for Kungfu Restaurant Co, China's top Chinese fast-food brand. Collaborated with project managers, engineers, and the marketing team, we delivered an omnichannel online order system (App, Kiosk, Dashboard) with a design system. The project raised online customer retention to 55% and helped the company ready for the unexpected COVID-19 pandemic.

 $2017-2018 \qquad \textbf{Junior UX Designer} \quad \textbf{Runwise Co}.$

Guangzhou, China

I crafted interfaces, illustrations and infographics for Refuel (Ji Neng), an e-learning app on lean-product, agile management and other skills.

2016 Interaction Design Intern ETU Design

Guangzhou / Shenzhen / Hong Kong, China

I collaborated with senior designers and user researchers to design user flow, wireframes interfaces. Clients included China Mobile HK, China Merchants Bank.

FEATURES & AWARDS

2021 Featured Project Complexity Education Project

Individual project "Bubble Trouble" was featured in a column of Massimo Conte, Editorial Coordinator of the Complexity Education Project.

2018 Annual Smart Retail Services WeChat

Team project "Kungfu Order" received the Wechat Mini App annual award

sylvester.lau@outlook.com

+44 07513 880183

130 Elephant Road, London SE17 1EX

View LinkedIn profile

LANGUAGE

English

IELTS 7.5 / CEFR C1

Chinese Mandarin

Native Speaker

Cantonese

Native Speaker

SKILLS

User Interviews
Interactive Prototyping
Design System
Data Visualisation
Data-driven Design
Product Strategy
Co-design Workshop
System Thinking
Design Management
User Testing

Life Learner

TOOLS

Figma / Sketch
Physical Model
HTML / CSS / JavaScript
Github
Notion
After Effects

Always trying new tools:)